[{"question":"An even-parity checker indicates a parity error for which received data and parity bit?","answers":{"a":"data = 1111111 parity = 1","b":"data = 1001001 parity = 0","c":"data = 1110000 parity = 1","d":"data = 0000000 parity = 0"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"In even parity system, the parity bit","answers":{"a":"Is transmitted with the data bits","b":"Is a zero if the data has an even number of one bits","c":"Is adjusted to make an even number of bits","d":"All of the above"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"In odd parity system, which of the following will generate high parity bit","answers":{"a":"1100010","b":"1001001","c":"1000000","d":"1010101"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"Which of the following is referred to as an equality gate?","answers":{"a":"OR","b":"XOR","c":"XNOR","d":"AND"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"What is a parity bit?","answers":{"a":"An error detection is achieved by adding an extra bit","b":"Bit generated during data transmission","c":"After addition, the carry is found","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"The BCD number 1101011 has _______ parity?","answers":{"a":"Odd","b":"Both even and odd","c":"Even","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"Parity generation and checking is used to detect","answers":{"a":"When a binary counter counts incorrectly","b":"Errors in arithmetic in computers","c":"Errors in binary data transmission","d":"Which of two no. is greater"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"An exclusive OR gate will invert a signal on one input if the other output is","answers":{"a":"Always high","b":"Connected to same signal","c":"Grounded","d":"Inverted"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"Parity bit coding may not be used for","answers":{"a":"Error in more than single bit","b":"Which bit is in error","c":"Both A and B","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"Select the statement that best describes the parity method of error detection:","answers":{"a":"Parity checking is best suited for detecting double bit error that occur during the transmission of codes from one location to another.","b":"Parity checking is not suitable for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.","c":"Parity checking is best suited for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.","d":"Parity checking is capable of detecting and correcting errors in transmitted codes."},"correctAnswer":"c"}]